# Peter Musembi Wambua

Resolute, goal-oriented cybersecurity individual experienced in ethical hacking, penetration testing, vulnerability analysis, network security, and security operations. Energetic, teachable, and technical-minded individual. I possess exceptional skills in scripting with Python and C, Red Team toolkits such as Metasploit and Burp Suite, and SOC tools like SIEM, EDR, and SOAR tools.

Nairobi, Kenya **Phone:** +254714873020

Mail: peterwambua025@gmail.com
GitHub: github.com/wambuapeter
Socials: LinkedIn Twitter Portfolio
Blog: https://thecyberlearner.github.io/

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Cyb3rk1math1 — CTF Player

July 2022 - PRESENT

- Contributed to CTFs with this award-winning team leading to a consistent top 4 placement in all CTF competitions participated in, showcasing expertise and teamwork skills in cybersecurity challenges.
- Specialized in penetration testing challenges, including web, Android, and boot2root, leading to a 90% success rate in solving challenges within these categories.
- Collaborated with team members to develop innovative solutions to problems, completing over 100 challenges across various categories, and demonstrating teamwork and problem-solving skills.

# **Hackerbro Technologies**, Remote — Red Team Engineer intern

July 2023 - October 2023

- Conducted penetration testing simulations on over 15 systems, identifying and exploiting multiple vulnerabilities, thereby enhancing the organizations' cybersecurity resilience.
- Specialized in application security assessments, successfully identifying and remediating high-risk vulnerabilities in critical applications, reducing the organization's exposure to potential cyber threats.
- Generated comprehensive reports on penetration testing activities, highlighting over 10 key findings and recommendations, leading to over 20% improvement in the organization's overall security posture.

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Dedan Kimathi University of Technology** — BSC in Computer Science

August 2020 - May 2024

- Did well in my degree achieving a second upper division
- Demonstrated leadership by founding the Cyber Security Club of Kimathi and leading technical sessions. An active member of the Google Developers Students Club.

## **ALX Africa Holberton School,** — Software Engineering certificate

June 2021 - May 2022

- Learned Linux basics, C, Python, Git, and project collaboration.
- Learned web development using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript then manipulated the back-end with Python.

# **PROJECTS**

# ${\bf Django\ Password\ Manager-\underline{https://github.com/Wambuapeter/BadPass}}$

• A secure password manager implemented using Django and using the best security features

## Undergraduates API — <a href="https://github.com/Wambuapeter/undergradAPI">https://github.com/Wambuapeter/undergradAPI</a>

• This is a flask API to provide undergraduates with mentorship and sponsorship programs

# Airline project — <a href="https://github.com/Wambuapeter/AirlineProject">https://github.com/Wambuapeter/AirlineProject</a>

This is an airline booking system I built on Java applets

## SKILLS

- Penetration Testing and Vulnerability Assessment
- Security Operations Log Monitoring and Events Investigation
- Active Directory and Wireless Penetration Testing
- Networking, Linux, Python Scripting
- Web Development and Security Django
- API Development and Security Flask

## **HUMAN SKILLS**

- Project Management
- Communication Skills
- Problem-solving
- Leadership

## Certifications

- Certified Network Security Practitioner(CNSP) <u>Link</u>
- Practical Ethical Hacking(PEH) <u>Link</u>
- Certified Threat Hunter by VTFoundation <u>Link</u>